You don't get to 500 million friends without making a few enemies.
The Social Network is a drama film directed by David Fincher.
In 2003, Harvard undergrad and computer programmer Mark Zuckerberg begins work on a new
concept that eventually turns into the global social network known as Facebook.
Six years later, Mark is one of the youngest billionaires ever, but his unprecedented success leads to both personal and
legal complications when he ends up on the receiving end of two lawsuits, one involving his former friend.
Mark Zuckerberg, played by Jesse Eisenberg.
Eduardo Saverin, played by Andrew Garfield.
Cameron Winklevoss / Tyler Winklevoss, played by Armie Hammer.
Tyler Winklevoss (Body Double), played by Josh Pence.
Sean Parker, played by Justin Timberlake.
Divya Narendra, played by Max Minghella.
The Social Network is a 2010 American biographical drama film
directed by David Fincher and written by Aaron Sorkin.
Based on the 2009 book The Accidental Billionaires by Ben Mezrich, the film
portrays the founding of the social networking website Facebook.
It stars Jesse Eisenberg as Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg, with Andrew Garfield as Eduardo Saverin, Justin
Timberlake as Sean Parker, Armie Hammer as Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss, and Max Minghella as Divya Narendra.
Neither Zuckerberg nor any other Facebook staff were involved with the
project, although Saverin was a consultant for Mezrich's book.
Production began when Sorkin signed on to write the screenplay.
Principal photography began that same year in October in
Cambridge, Massachusetts, and lasted until November.
Additional scenes were shot in California, in the
cities of Los Angeles and Pasadena.
Trent Reznor and Atticus Ross of Nine Inch Nails composed the film's
award-winning score, which was released on September 28, 2010.
The film premiered at the New York Film Festival on September 24, 2010, and was released
theatrically in the United States on October 1, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
A major commercial success, the film grossed $224 million on a $40
million budget and was widely acclaimed by critics.
It was named one of the best films of the year by 447 critics, and named
the best by 110 critics, the most of any film that year.
It was also chosen by the National Board of Review as the best film of 2010.
At the 83rd Academy Awards, it received eight nominations, including for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best
Actor for Eisenberg, and won for Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Original Score, and Best Film Editing.
It also received awards for Best Motion Picture – Drama, Best Director, Best
Screenplay, and Best Original Score at the 68th Golden Globe Awards.
The Social Network has maintained a strong reputation since its initial release, and is
commonly ranked by critics as one of the best films of the 2010s and 21st century.
The Writers Guild of America ranked Sorkin's screenplay
the third greatest of the 21st century.
The factual accuracy is, however, largely contested.
In 2024, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
A sequel titled The Social Reckoning with Sorkin writing and
directing is scheduled for release on October 9, 2026.
The film explores themes of hacker, based on novel or book, boston,
massachusetts, ex-girlfriend, harvard university.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.